Okay, let's get to solving this. Um, I
think the very first thing we want to do
is we want to gather all the questions
and put them in local storage. So, let's
do that. Um, and I'm going to do that
using a function, um,
get questions and load local storage.
And I'm going to have that be an
asynchronous function because I am going
to use Axios.
So
we actually have Axios up here. So we
can just go ahead and grab it. Um so get
questions and load local storage. So
we'll say let data equal await.
Um and then we'll say
axios.get.
And then let's go grab that API.
And that should give us the results. So
let's just log those. And
see where that gets us.
And then if it's an asynchronous
um function, I do have to actually call
it. So let's call it and save that. And
then let's go check our console. So if
we check our console, we've got this
data object. And in the data object, it
has more data. So inside of data, there
is a data object. And inside of that,
there is a results object. So let's go
back over to our code.
And let's unpack and grab the data out.
And let's print data.res.
And save that. And now if we come over,
we get this array where it's a an array
of objects um with a question.
And then it also has a correct answer.
So let's go back over to our code and
let's store that in local storage. So to
do that, say local storage dot set item.
And the item we want to set is trivia.
And what do we want to set it to? Well,
um, remember we do need to convert this
into a nice string storeable format. So,
we're going to say JSON.stringify
and the thing we're stringifying is
data.s.
So, now
we'll save this
and we'll come check our code. And if we
go to application here in trivia, you
can see that it stores 10 questions.
Awesome. All right. So I think the next
thing we'd want to do is we'd want to
write a function that checks local
storage for a question and if it exists
displays it on screen. If it doesn't
then it calls our last function and then
displays it on screen. So let's go back
over to our code. So let's write that
second function. const get
question
from storage.
And we'll also make this an async
function.
All right. So, um want to see if
um
local storage.get item
trivia.
And that will give us back the item
um if it exists.
Um, if it doesn't exist, then that means
that we don't have a trivia key and we
don't have any trivia questions and we
need to get them. So, I'm going to say
if it doesn't exist, go out and get
those trivia questions. And we actually
already wrote that function. So, we'll
say await
question from storage.
So, what that does is it allows us to
set local storage.
Once we're done, um, we now once we get
to this line, we know the only way to
get to this line is if the trivia key
exists or we just created the trivia key
in this function. So we know at this
point the trivia key exists. So now we
can grab a question. So we'll say let
um
let
questions equal um JSON.parse
local storage. Get item and we're
looking for trivia.
And then we'll say let question and
correct answer
equal
questions.
So questions.pop goes into the array,
grabs out an object, and then we are
going to dstructure that object and take
out the question and the correct answer.
Um, if you look over at the
instructions, it says to store the
correct answer in session storage. So,
let's go ahead and do that. So, we'll
say session storage set item correct
answer
and we'll set it equal to the correct
answer.
And then now we need to um display on
stream um the correct uh the question.
So uh let's go ahead and we need to
access the div id of question. So let's
use jQuery and we'll say we're looking
for the question
and then we want to set its HTML
equal to
the question.
All right, let's call this function and
make sure it's working.
So we'll say get
question
from storage.
So if we save this,
we come over to our code
and we reload the page.
It looks like it did not put anything on
the page. But let's look at the
application. So um we've got our trivia
questions and in session storage we have
that the correct answer is true.
Um,
so it looks like the thing that didn't
work is displaying the HTML of the
question.
So let's see.
It would help if I spelled question
correctly. Question.
And down here, if I spelled that
correctly as well, question.
And save that. And now let's go see.
Okay, the sum of all the numbers on a
roulette wheel is 666. And then we can
go look in our application and we can
see that the correct answer is true. So
now what we want to do is we want to
make these buttons work. So now we have
to have something that checks if the
button clicked has the same text as the
correct answer in session storage. So
let's go over there and let's write that
question and we'll call it check
function and we'll call it check answer.
So we'll say const check answer equals
and we'll receive an event
and we'll say if e dot target dot
um
inner text
is exactly equal to
session storage.get get item
correct answer.
Then what do we want to do? We want to
alert
correct.
And then we want to call get [sighs]
uh question from storage to grab a new
question. Otherwise, we want to alert
try again. And really, it's true false.
So there's really only one other answer
that it could be. Um, and when do we
want this check answer to get called? We
want it to get called when they click on
a button. So, let's go ahead and attach
it to the button using jQuery. So, let's
grab the true
button.
And
when it gets clicked, we want to call
check answer. And then let's just copy
this down. And we'll make this the false
button.
And when it gets clicked, oh, and those
are both IDs, which means I do need to
add the hashtag in front of them. And
we'll save that.
And then we'll come over here. So the
sum of all numbers on a roulette wheel
is 666. And we can check session
storage. And it says the correct answer
is true. So if I click that, I get
correct.
And it moves on. Or rather, it didn't.
It's still displaying the same question.
So we can now find the correct answer.
So what we want to do is we want to um
when they get the when they grab a new
question, we want to remove the old
question.
Sorry, thinking through how we want to
do this. So when they get the correct
question, we want to grab a new question
from local storage. And we should be
slowly depleting local storage. So um
this is removing it from local storage
and displaying it on the screen but
we're never resetting local storage. So
local storage is still storing the
original thing. So what we need to do is
we need to restore local storage. So
we'll say local storage dot set item
trivia
and we want to set its value equal to
JSON stringify and we want to stringify
the questions array that now we'll have
one less question because of this pop
and then
we actually only want to do that if
there's even a question left. If there's
not, we just want to remove the trivia
item so that it knows that it should
grab new qu it should um
get questions and load local storage.
So
let's go ahead and write
that if statement.
So we're going to say if questions
dolength
is less than or equal to zero
then we're just going to local storage
remove item
trivia.
Otherwise
we're going to set it equal to the
remaining questions. So let's save that
and see if this works. Okay. Sum of all
numbers on roulette wheel is 66. We'll
say true. says correct and it says in
Star Trek's Cllingon are commonly
referred to as black eyes. It says the
correct answer is false. So I'm going
say false. It's going to say okay. I'm
going to check local storage and you can
see that there are seven questions
remaining. So let's answer the remaining
seven questions. So it's true.
We'll answer this one wrong. Says try
again. We'll hit false and then we'll
say false.
And then we'll say false.
And let's check local storage. If we
look at trivia questions, there are
three questions left. And so we'll say
true.
There should be two questions left now.
False. One question left now. And let's
check local storage. There's one
question left. Um, so this one will
answer true.
And now if we look in local storage,
there are no questions left. The answer
to this one is false.
So, we called our API and now if we
check local storage, we're back to
having um
nine questions left because we are
displaying the 10th question on screen.
All right. Um so, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to go in and add some
comments.
So, I'm going to say get questions and
load local storage.
um
grab questions from storage and display
and set correct answer. And then here
we're going to say check if there
are questions left. If not, grab new
questions.
Um here we're going to say um
grab the questions and set correct
answer and
and display.
Here we're going to say um reset
um local storage
based on remaining questions.
And then here we're going to say set
correct answer and display question.
Here in the check answer we're going to
see say check if button has the correct
text.
Here we'll say add event listeners.
And here we'll say
we actually don't need that one anymore.
So let's save this and run our code one
more time.
Oh
actually we do have one more portion
that we need to do. Um I was calling
if we put it back I was calling get
question from storage when the page
loaded. If I want to do this during
during using jQuery, then I will say
look for the body tag and when it's
ready I want you to call get question
from storage. Then we can remove this
last item and save. And if we come back
over um it looks like our game is back
to working and the correct answer of
this one is true.
And obviously this game will be a lot
more fun if you play it with the console
closed.